Peter Hurd and Henriette Wyeth Hurd
Archives of American Art, Smithsonian Institution
- Correspondence, 1917-1989, undated, Series 2:; (boxes 1-4, 3.5 linear ft.)
  - Business Correspondence of Peter Hurd, 1923-1989, undated, 2.3:
    - Allred, Dr. E. C. - America The Beautiful Fund (Box 2, Reel 5126)
    - American Artist, 1962-1974 (Box 2, Reel 5126)
    - American Artists Group, Inc. - American Broadcasting Company (Box 2, Reel 5126)
    - American Embassy in Mexico, 1965-1966 (Box 2, Reel 5126)
    - American Federation of Arts, 1938-1947 (Box 2, Reel 5126)
    - American Heritage, 1964-1975 (Box 2, Reel 5126)
    - American Institute of Architects - American Orchid Society, Inc. (Box 2, Reel 5126)
    - American Watercolor Society, 1962-1973, (2 folders) (Box 2, Reel 5126)
    - AMFAC (American Factors, Ltd.) - Anderman, George G. (Box 2, Reel 5126)
    - Anderson, Clinton P., 1941-1971 (Box 2, Reel 5126)
    - Anderson, Donald B. - Anderson, Mildred K. (Box 2, Reel 5126)
    - Anderson, Robert O., 1954-1972 (Box 2, Reel 5126)
    - Andrews/Nelson/Whitehead, Inc. - Arizona Bank (Box 2, Reel 5126)
    - Arizona Highways, 1952-1974, (5 folders) (Box 2, Reel 5126)
    - Arizona State Fair - Armstrong (Box 2, Reel 5126)
    - Artesia: College of Artesia, 1967-1971 (Box 2, Reel 5126)
    - Arthur, Zinn - Art in America (Box 2, Reel 5126)
    - Art Institute of Chicago, 1935-1941 (Box 2, Reel 5126)
    - Artists Equity Association, Inc. - Asia Foundation (Box 2, Reel 5126)
    - Aspen Institute for Humanistic Studies, 1962-1974 (Box 2, Reel 5126)
    - Associated American Artists, 1936-1975, (10 folders) (Box 2, Reel 5126-5127)
    - Aston, Rogers - Austin, Flavius (Box 2, Reel 5127)
    - Ayer: N. W. Ayer & Son, Inc., 1942-1950, (3 folders) (Box 2, Reel 5127)
    - Ayers, Thomas G. - Aylward, Nell (Box 3, Reel 5127)
    - Babbitt, Bruce - Baker, Frederick (Box 3, Reel 5127)
    - Baker, Straus, 1964-1968 (Box 3, Reel 5127)
    - Bales, Bob - Ballantine, Bill (Box 3, Reel 5127)
    - Ballin, Hugo - Barry, Claude and Dana (Box 3, Reel 5127)
    - Bass, Perry, R., 1958-1978 (Box 3, Reel 5127)
    - Bates, Jack, 1951 (Box 3, Reel 5127)
    - Beal, Carlton, 1968-1970 (Box 3, Reel 5127)
    - Beam: Jim Beam Bottle Project, 1969-1970 (Box 3, Reel 5127)
    - Beitz, Lester - Biddle, John H. (Box 3, Reel 5127)
    - Biggs, John, Jr., 1937-1981, (2 folders) (Box 3, Reel 5127)
    - Bishop, John - Blaustein, Julian (Box 3, Reel 5127)
    - Blue Lake Project, 1969-1972 (Box 3, Reel 5127)
    - Blumenstock, Mrs. George - Bogle, Dorothy (Box 3, Reel 5127)
    - Bohemian Club, 1967-1969 (Box 3, Reel 5127)
    - Boise Art Association - Bonney, William (Box 3, Reel 5127)
    - Book of the Month Club, Inc., 1971-1972 (Box 3, Reel 5127)
    - Book Stall - Bowman, Frank (Box 3, Reel 5127)
    - Bradford, Dewey C., 1961-1965 (Box 3, Reel 5127)
    - Bradley, Palmer - Brice, Charles R. (Box 3, Reel 5127)
    - Briggs, James - Bunting, Mrs. Frederick W. (Box 3, Reel 5127)
    - Bureau of Reclamation, 1969-1974 (Box 3, Reel 5127)
    - Burgess, Ryk - Busch, Niven (Box 3, Reel 5127)
    - Business Men's Assurance, 1962-1972 (Box 3, Reel 5127)
    - Butcher, Mrs. Cary P. - Butoler, Olivia (Box 3, Reel 5127)
    - Bynner, Witter, 1940-1975 (Box 3, Reel 5127)
    - Byrom, Gilliam, 1973 (Box 3, Reel 5127)
    - Cabell, Charles P. - Carlin Galleries (Box 3, Reel 5127)
    - Carroll, John M., 1969-1971 (Box 3, Reel 5127)
    - Carter, Jimmy, envelope fragment, undated (Box 3, Reel 5127)
    - Circle Gallery, Ltd., 1972-1974, (3 folders) (Box 3, Reel 5127)
    - Colorado: University of Colorado, undated (Box 3, Reel 5127)
    - Copley, James S., 1967-1973 (Box 3, Reel 5127)
    - Cosmos Club, 1960-1967 (Box 3, Reel 5127)
    - Country Gentleman, 1941-1952 (Box 3, Reel 5127)
    - Coward-McCann, Inc., 1944-1957 (Box 3, Reel 5127)
    - Craver Farms, 1982 (Box 3, Reel 5127)
    - Daeuble - Dallas Museum of Fine Arts (Box 3, Reel 5127)
    - Dallas Terminal Annex, 1938-1978 (Box 3, Reel 5127)
    - Dalrymple, Mrs. Glen - Dartmouth College (Box 3, Reel 5127)
    - Datsun endorsement, 1972-1979 (Box 3, Reel 5127)
    - Daughtery, Frank - Davidson, Harry M. (Box 3, Reel 5127)
    - Davis, John - Deane, Martha (Box 3, Reel 5127)
    - Decorators' Showcase, 1967 (Box 3, Reel 5127)
    - Deere & Company - Desert Magazine Art Gallery (Box 3, Reel 5127)
    - Dietz, Mrs. Robert - Dixon, George (Box 3, Reel 5127)
    - Dobie - Paisano Project, 1965-1966 (Box 3, Reel 5127)
    - Dobson, B. C. - Douglas Art Association (Box 3, Reel 5127)
    - Dow, James - Dysart, Cabot (Box 3, Reel 5127)
    - Easter, Sister Claretta - Easterling, Ross (Box 3, Reel 5127)
    - Eastern New Mexico University, 1963-1979 (Box 3, Reel 5127-5128)
    - Eastern Washington State Historical Society - Eckman, Mary (Box 3, Reel 5128)
    - Edinburgh Regional College - Eiseman, Douglass W. (Box 3, Reel 5128)
    - Eisenstaedt, Alfred - Elms Gallery (Box 3, Reel 5128)
    - El Paso Museum of Art, 1961-1978 (Box 3, Reel 5128)
    - Embry, W. Glenn - Emmet, John (Box 3, Reel 5128)
    - Encyclopedia Britannica, 1944-1977 (Box 3, Reel 5128)
    - English, Frances Bonnell - Evans, Dorothy T. (Box 3, Reel 5128)
    - Evans, Elinor - Ezell, James Kerry (Box 3, Reel 5128)
    - Fairbanks, Mrs. Douglas - Family Circle Magazine, 1954 (Box 3, Reel 5128)
    - Farm Journal, 1950-1970 (Box 3, Reel 5128)
    - Farnsworth Television & Radio Corp. - Faudree, William (Box 3, Reel 5128)
    - Fauntleroy, O. W. - Fideler Company (Box 3, Reel 5128)
    - Field Enterprises Corp., 1965-1975, (2 folders) (Box 3, Reel 5128)
    - Fielding, William - Film Enterprises (Box 3, Reel 5128)
    - Fine Arts Commission, 1959-1962 (Box 3, Reel 5128)
    - Finley, David Edward - Fireman's Fund (Box 3, Reel 5128)
    - First National Bank of Albuquerque, 1970 (Box 3, Reel 5128)
    - First National Bank of Chicago, 1962-1974 (Box 3, Reel 5128)
    - Flannery, Vaughan - Fleischmann, Justin and Lillian (Box 3, Reel 5128)
    - Fleming, Joseph - Fogg Art Museum (Box 3, Reel 5128)
    - Foote, Cone, & Belding, 1949-1955 (Box 3, Reel 5128)
    - Ford, Jesse Hill, 1965 (Box 3, Reel 5128)
    - Ford Motor Company, 1950-1969 (Box 3, Reel 5128)
    - Ford, Merrill - Foster, Robert (Box 3, Reel 5128)
    - Foust, Chester - Frank, Paul A. (Box 4, Reel 5128)
    - Franklin Mint, 1970-1973 (Box 4, Reel 5128)
    - Franklin Pierce College - Fundingsland, Mrs. S. E. (Box 4, Reel 5128)
    - Georgia: University of Georgia, 1980 (Box 4, Reel 5128)
    - Goddard, Robert H., 1964-1971 (Box 4, Reel 5128)
    - Golden Anniversary Friendship Flight, 1962 (Box 4, Reel 5128)
    - Guelph: University of Guelph (Ontario, Canada), 1977 (Box 4, Reel 5128)
    - Hacker, George - Haeberle, Peter (Box 4, Reel 5128)
    - Hagberg, Peter - Halliburton, Erle (Box 4, Reel 5128)
    - Hallmark Cards, Inc., 1949-1962 (Box 4, Reel 5128)
    - Halsey, Admiral - Harman, Fred (Box 4, Reel 5128)
    - Harmon, H. R., 1955-1956 (Box 4, Reel 5128)
    - Harper, Mrs. Gerald - Harrison, Milton (Box 4, Reel 5128)
    - Harvard Art Review - Hathaway, C. (Box 4, Reel 5128)
    - Haverford College, 1951-1981 (Box 4, Reel 5128)
    - Hawkins, Gardiner - Haynsworth, Mrs. R. F. (Box 4, Reel 5128)
    - Headquarters [U. S. Air Force], 1942-1976 (Box 4, Reel 5128)
    - Headquarters of Fifteenth Air Force, 1955-1966 (Box 4, Reel 5128)
    - Healey, Giles Greville - Heineman, Ben W. (Box 4, Reel 5128)
    - Helbis, John and Shirley - Hensley, Jackson (Box 4, Reel 5128)
    - Hercules Powder Company, 1953-1974 (Box 4, Reel 5128)
    - Hergesheimer, Joseph - Hickman, Charles S. (Box 4, Reel 5128)
    - High Mesa College - Hirschl & Adler (Box 4, Reel 5128)
    - Hissom, R. J. - Hogsett, Glade C. (Box 4, Reel 5128)
    - Holden, W. Curry, 1950-1977 (Box 4, Reel 5128)
    - Holle, Charles G. - Homer, Jack (Box 4, Reel 5128)
    - Hondo Valley Traffic Safety, 1963 (Box 4, Reel 5128)
    - Honolulu Art Association - Horgan, Ed (Box 4, Reel 5128)
    - Horwitz, Mary Lou - House & Garden (Box 4, Reel 5129)
    - Houston Chronicle - Hulse, Max D. (Box 4, Reel 5129)
    - Humble Oil & Refining Company - Hurley, Wilson D. (Box 4, Reel 5129)
    - Hutchins, Susan, 1923-1928 (Box 4, Reel 5129)
    - MacNider, Jack - McKee, John J. (Box 4, Reel 5129)
    - National Academy of Design, 1982-1989 (Box 4, Reel 5129)
    - New Mexico: Office of the Governor, 1981 (Box 4, Reel 5129)
    - New Mexico: University of New Mexico, Albuquerque, 1975-1978 (Box 4, Reel 5129)
    - Nixon, Pat/Julie Eisenhower, 1978-1980, (2 folders) (Box 4, Reel 5129)
    - Oklahoma: University of Oklahoma Press, 1975-1977 (Box 4, Reel 5129)
    - Rainier: Prince Rainier of Monaco - Rummell, Mrs. W. B. (Box 4, Reel 5129)
    - St. John's College, 1963-1977 (Box 4, Reel 5129)
    - St. Vincent Hospital - Suzette International (Box 4, Reel 5129)
    - Swallow Press, Inc., 1969-1977, (3 folders) (Box 4, Reel 5129)
    - Tankersley, Mrs. Garvin - Texaco (Box 4, Reel 5129)
    - Texas A&M University, 1980-1982 (Box 4, Reel 5129)
    - Texas Centennial Exposition, 1936 (Box 4, Reel 5129)
    - Texas - New Mexico Library Association, 1976-1977 (Box 4, Reel 5129)
    - Texas: University of Texas, Austin, 1964-1979 (Box 4, Reel 5129)
    - Thompson, Daniel V. - Treidel, Mrs. Walter (Box 4, Reel 5129)
    - Trigg, Mrs. - Twaddell, Kristie (Box 4, Reel 5129)
    - United States Information Agency, 1975-1976 (Box 4, Reel 5129)
    - Vance, Mrs, Alex - Vance, “Monk”, 1975 (Box 4, Reel 5129)
    - Vinson, Bailie, 1959-1978 (Box 4, Reel 5129)
    - Vollum, Orville, 1973-1975 (Box 4, Reel 5129)
    - Wagley, Philip F. - Walbridge, Norton S. (Box 4, Reel 5129)
    - Walker Air Force Base, 1954-1967 (Box 4, Reel 5129)
    - Walters, Richard H. - Waxman, Lilo (Box 4, Reel 5129)
    - Webster, Jack - Willner, Catherine (Box 4, Reel 5129)
    - Wilmington Savings Fund - Woods, Carol R. (Box 4, Reel 5129)
    - Woodsmall, Warren O. - Wyoming: University of Wyoming (Box 4, Reel 5129)
- Notes, undated, Series 3:; (box 4, 1 folder)
  - Notes, undated (Box 4, Reel 5129)
- Writings, 1980-1985, undated, Series 4:; (box 4, 12 folders)
  - Miscellaneous Poems, undated, 4.1:
    - Untitled Miscellaneous Poems, undated (Box 4, Reel 5129)
  - Writings by Paul Horgan, 1980-1985, undated, 4.2:
    - “Parody of Edith Sitwell 'A La Facade,' ” undated (Box 4, Reel 5129)
    - “The Annotated Clerihew: 'Brief Lives,' ” undated (Box 4, Reel 5129)
    - Review of Stravinsky: Selected Correspondence, undated (Box 4, Reel 5129)
    - “Foreword” [re: Bob Anderson], undated (Box 4, Reel 5129)
    - “Henriette Wyeth and Her Approach to Painting,” undated (Box 4, Reel 5129)
    - “Henriette Wyeth,” 1980 (Box 4, Reel 5129)
    - “Introduction” [to Paul Hurd's Letters], 1982 (Box 4, Reel 5129)
    - “A Clutch of Clerihews: For Triny's Birthday,” 1983 (Box 4, Reel 5129)
    - “Not to Avoid the Obvious,” 1984 (Box 4, Reel 5129)
    - “Of America East and West,” 1985 (Box 4, Reel 5129)
  - Writings by Others, undated, 4.3:
    - Introduction to Paul Horgan's Field Notes by David McCullough, undated (Box 4, Reel 5129)
- Artwork, 1940, undated, Series 5:; (box 4, 2 folders)
  This series contains three drawings by Peter Hurd and a drawing by Paul Horgan.
  - Drawings by Peter Hurd, undated (Box 4, Reel 5129)
  - Drawing by Paul Horgan, 1940 (Box 4, Reel 5129)
- Printed Material, 1928-1989, undated, Series 6:; (box 4, 14 folders)
  This series contains clippings, exhibition catalogs, press releases, and a brochure.
  - Clippings, 1936-1988, undated, (7 folders) (Box 4, Reel 5129)
  - Exhibition catalogs, 1928-1985, undated, (5 folders) (Box 4, Reel 5129)
  - Press releases, 1978-1989 (Box 4, Reel 5129)
  - Brochure for “Valley in October,” 1980 (Box 4, Reel 5129)
- Photographs of Friends, 1977, undated, Series 7:; (box 4, 1 folder)
  This series contains two photographs of Paul Horgan and an unidentified man.
  - Photographs of friends, 1977, undated (Box 4, Reel 5129)